

Mike Grace software engineer



mikegrace.tech



mike@mikegrace.tech



440-829-5501



/mikeegrace



/TravelFiend

TECH KNOWLEDGE

Languages
Javascript
Python
Shopify Liquid
HTML

CSS Ruby

<u>Frontend</u> React / Redux

React Hooks

Sass

Backend Node.js Express Mongoose <u>Tools</u>

Github Postman Heroku

Heroku Netlify TravisCl VS Code

Boomi

Database

PostgreSQL MongoDB

MongoDi

Testing

Jest QUnit Enzyme

THINGS I LIKE

- Mountain Biking
- Travelling
- Fishing
- Page Fillers
- Jokes

BACKGROUND & PROFILE

Full-Stack software engineer experienced in building and deploying apps using React, React Native, Shopify Liquid, Python and both relational and document databases. Enjoys finding creative ways of solving intricate problems and experimenting with and implementing new technologies. Makes a point to learn something new every day.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Schoolhouse / Food52

March 2021 - Present

Software Engineer

- Developed and maintained Shopify Theme using Liquid and Javascript, and numerous Shopify APIs.
- Worked closely with marketing team to execute design requests using Sass, BEM, while communicating any limitations of thirdparty apps.
- Integrated and customized third-party Shopify apps.
- Created and modified PostgreSQL database schemas and tables, and populated those tables with data from SAP ByDesign using Odata requests.
- Automated tasks for numerouscross-functional partners using Python scripts and Boomi processes.

Lifetime Optimization Inc. March 2020 – March 2021 Full-Stack Software Engineer GOOGLE PLAY // APPLE STORE

- Collaborated remotely with one other dev to launch a mobile app and accompanying web app/backend, playing the role of architect, developer and maintainer. Our app, NMConnect, gives users access to health and wellness resources.
- Developed our Mobile app using React Native with Expo.
- Created an accompanying web app using React, as well as a RESTful API/backend using MongoDB, to give stakeholders access to update app content and send push notifications.
- Helped save a \$1.5 million contract with the State of New Mexico, as well as helping to secure an additional \$200K of funding.

Sykes Enterprises

May 2013 – July 2018

IT Logistics Specialist

- Performed system inspections with detailed inspection notes.
- Helped to reduce preparation and deployment time by organizing the inventory and streamlining workflow for increased productivity.
- Imaged computers for client needs before shipping to employees

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Alchemy Code Lab

Full-Stack Software Engineering 2020

Ohio University

BFA in Printmaking 2011